Great job finishing this section on project management foundations I know we covered a lot of material
in this section but this is some really important material really sets a good foundation or a cornerstone
for the remainder of the course as we work towards you passing the PMP.
So in the section we talked about what is a project and what a project is not that how does that affect
organizations would they go about selecting projects as operations or is it a project we talked about
the temporary nature of projects that projects are temporary teams or temporary and sometimes what projects
create the unique product service or result that that can be temporary as well.
So we look to just a temporary nature of projects.
We talked about a very important term that we'll see a few more times throughout the course is business
value that projects create business value.
Very important for your exam business.
Now you have a clear understanding about that.
We talked about why projects are even created so the project the initiation contex why projects are
selected and initiated and funded in an organization we looked at the project management application
areas and we've been defined Well what is project management having a clear understanding of what's
project management.
How can it work in all of these different application areas.
How can it work in construction or in healthcare in I.T. that it's a set of principles of the framework
is the generally accepted practices and then we can tailor those practices for what's appropriate in
our organization or in our discipline.
We looked at reviewing the project lifecycle and then compare that to the project management lifecycle.
All right a lot of information I know we have a lot yet to cover.
We're just getting going here and of course you've got some good momentum.
Keep it up.
I want you to keep moving forward.
I'll see you in the next lecture.